What do you think is going to happen
with Iran? We the bombing that happened
with the US bombing the the nuclear
sites and then Israel and Iran going
back and forth and there's talks that
there's going to be maybe a continuation
of that before December of this year.
>> I talked to a lot of very serious Iran
experts, scholars in Washington. As
recently as yesterday, I talked to
Treata Parcy, who's probably the most
important Iran scholar in America, and
universally they believe that that
Israel will attack Iran again before the
1st of December. Yes.
>> I I mean, they kind of have to if you
look at the opportunity that they have
to do so because you have an
administration that will kind of look
the other way and has given Israel the
opportunity to do so.
>> Yes. Uh, so if the administration
changes or the midterm elections change,
that window's gone.
>> It's got to happen now.
>> It's got to happen fast. And also,
>> it's a shame. It's a shame because I'll
tell you, the the JCPOA, whether the
Republicans liked it or not, was
actually working. It was exactly the
same inspection regime that we had with
the Iraqis from UN Security Council uh
resolution 986 and 1060, right?
Inspectors were able to go in
unannounced. There were lead seals on
every site. There were cameras
everywhere that were doing live feeds
back to the United Nations in uh in
Vienna. It was actually working. But
Donald Trump pulled us out and then the
Iranians started enriching uranium, not
to weapons grade, but enriching it to a
higher uh level than it had been
enriched. And then the Israelis said,
"Oh my god, they're going to build a
bomb." Despite the fact that the CIA had
published three separate national
intelligence estimates saying that the
Iranians are not building a bomb,
they're enriching slightly. So, they're
keeping their options open, but they're
not building a bomb. And then Netanyahu
said, and this is another thing
Netanyahu, I was in the CIA a long time.
No matter who was president, literally
every single time Netanyahu came to
Washington, he'd say, "Please bomb Iran.
Please bomb Iran. Please bomb Iran." And
every single president said, "We're not
going to bomb Iran for you." Until this
one,
>> John, what was the what was the idea
though? Bomb Iran and then what? Regime
change. What was the plan?
>> The eventual goal of course is regime
change.
>> But that's very difficult with that
country because it's not
>> extraordinarily difficult.
>> Yeah. It's not one person. It's it's
embedded in the entire
>> I mentioned to you offline that as much
as I hate and disagree with everything
that Hillary Clinton stands for and has
said, she did say one thing about Iran
that she was exactly right about. She
said Iran is actually not a theocracy.
Iran is a military dictatorship. It's
not run by the Ayatollas. It's run by
the IRGC and that makes it more
dangerous.
>> Doesn't the Ayatollah control the IRGC?
technically but on a day-to-day day
basis not not really no not anymore
100% absolutely
>> noi died
>> under Humeni
>> oh yeah
>> yes he absolutely did under k
it's really not in his bailey wick
>> so if Israel were to attack what do you
think their game plan is um I mean it
would have to be through ground forces
mainly because that's what
>> which would be impossible country's too
big, too many people, too mountainous.
>> Well, no, I didn't mean I didn't mean
Yeah, I agree with you. I don't think
ground force as in troops going in, but
I think indirectly covertly maybe going
into the country or they're already
Msad's already country.
>> They're already there picking off
nuclear scientists and generals all over
the country. And the the Israelis have
been very very successful in recruiting
Afghan illegal aliens,
>> which all the Afghans got deported after
this war. Right. Did they like with
lightning speed too?
>> They rounded up all the Afghans in the
country and just deported I think it was
like one one week.
>> Thousands of them.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. In one week everybody's expelled.
>> Yeah. Just complete. Whether you're
>> because there is no refugee program in
Iran. These people are literally
starving. They're on the street corners
begging for food, begging for clothing.
And then the Israelis say, "Hey, you
know, we'll give you 50 bucks if you
tell us where the general lives." And
they're like, "Yeah, he lives right
there. Here's $50. Oh, that's that's a
good investment if you're Israel.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's great intel
>> for pennies on the dollar.
>> Yeah.
>> So, what do you think that's going to
what's going to happen there if Israel
attacks? I think we are in an unusually
dangerous period right now
>> as America or
>> the whole world really got it
>> because
you know there was always this line that
American presidents wouldn't allow
Netanyahu to cross but now we have let
him cross it and the genie's out of the
bottle. You can't put it back in. And so
what does it mean? We bombed Iran on
behalf of the Israelis because we had
these bunker buster bombs, the 30,000
MOABs, right? Mother of all bombs. And
um at least that's what we called them
at the agency. And um the Israelis have
concluded that no, that's not good
enough. We didn't destroy all the
underground facilities. They were deeper
than we thought they were. And so we
have to use more or bigger or nuclear.
And we can't just doing keep doing these
pin pricks. We have to overthrow the
entire government. You can't overthrow
the entire government. It's
decentralized. It's just simply not
possible. And see, this is a beef I had
with American war planners, too. This is
something I learned early on at the
agency is there is never ever a plan to
get out, right? It's easy to go in and
just start killing people and overthrow
a government. It is almost impossible to
make a clean escape. And then what do
you do then? and you're in Iraq for 20
years and you're in Afghanistan for 20
years and you have 10,000 people dead
and then what do you do? You've killed 2
million people over there.
>> Iran's a little different because you
got 90 million population. It's huge.
>> You have the terrain. The education
level is different than Afghanistan.
Iraq.
>> That's right. It's a sophisticated
society. They're highly educated and
they're patriotic. Even if they don't
like the Ayatollas, they love their
country. Nobody wants to be invaded and
occupied by a foreign power.
>> Iranians are very pro-America. The
actual people are very pro-America.
>> But [clears throat] yeah, but to your
point, if they get attacked, then they
have no choice but to have to fight.
>> Yeah, that's the unfortunate thing.
>> Plus, you know, one of the things that
we as a country seem to not take into
consideration is what are the reactions
going to be from Russia and China?
They're not just going to sit there and
twiddle their thumbs and watch us
invade, you know, Iran. Well, Russia's
kind of bogged down with Ukraine and I
think China,
>> but they're winning. And the Russians
have not gone so far as to say that Iran
falls under their nuclear umbrella. They
could.
>> Yeah,
>> they haven't yet, but they're actually
winning in Ukraine. If they wanted to
divert troops to protect the Iranians,
that would only take a week or two. But
hasn't history shown that when a country
fights at two borders or two different
wars, they they fall?
>> Yeah. But what I'm saying is if they
wanted to just declare victory in
Ukraine and go home, just do a blitz.
>> They could just do that right now.
>> Yeah. Cuz what do the Russians want in
Ukraine? They want Donetsk and Luhansk,
>> which they have.
>> Which they have.
>> They want the Crimea, which they also
have.
>> Yeah.
>> The rest is gravy. I would think if that
were to happen, that scenario were to
happen, then China would just go after
Taiwan and just take Taiwan because they
would know.
>> See, and and I don't I'm probably in the
minority on that, but the Chinese
actually don't have a history of
imperialism. They they fought a little
border skirmish with North Vietnam in
the 70s. They've fought two little
skirmishes with India over the years,
most recently a year ago. just little,
you know, shots across the border.
Tibet, of course, they invaded and
occupied. That's different. The Chinese
have one foreign military base and as
nuts as it sounds, they share it with
us. It's in Djibouti. I've been there.
Camp Lemonet. When the
>> Where haven't you?
>> I know. The when the French pulled out,
they just abandoned Camp Lemonet. And
the Djiboutians asked us, "You want
this?" And we said, "Yeah, it's 16 miles
from Yemen. Sure, we'll take it." And
then the Chinese is like, "Yeah, we'll
take some, too." So there's literally a
chain link fence right down the middle.
And on the right side is the Americans
and on the left side is the Chinese.
That's the only Chinese military base in
the world outside of China. So it's not
like they're imperialists. And the
Chinese, you know, we're really the ones
who lead the charge saying that the
Chinese are always on the brink of
invading Taiwan. Even the Taiwan
government doesn't believe that's the
case.
>> Well, I mean, China doesn't recognize
Taiwan. They're all Chinese.
>> No, they're all Chinese. They're all
Chinese citizens. They all have Chinese
>> eventually. They'll be reunited.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The Chinese have never said
reunited by force. We say it.
>> I see.
>> Yeah.
>> That's the big difference.
>> Yeah. And then, you know, we send we
send the the Seventh Fleet to the South
China Sea. They're like, "The Chinese
are in the South China Sea." Yeah.
>> Cuz we're there.
>> Yeah. It's the South China Sea. What
What would our reaction be if the
Chinese brought an air aircraft carrier
to the Caribbean? We'd lose our minds.
So, I'm not worried about the Chinese as
an offensive force.
You know, there was a there was a
cartoon in The Onion this week that made
me laugh out loud. Um, it was about it
was a bunch of Chinese guys and they
were sitting like this and it said,
"China has changed its official policy
to just sit back and watch the American
government collapse on its own."
>> That's what it feels like.
>> Yeah. Yeah.